The human thirst for knowledge is the driving force behind our successful development as a species.
人类对知识的渴求，是我们这个物种得以成功发展的驱动力。
But curiosity can also be dangerous, leading to setbacks or even downfalls.
但好奇心也可能很危险，会导致挫折，甚至招致毁灭。
Given curiosity’s complexity, scientists have found it hard to define.
鉴于好奇心的复杂性，科学家们一直觉得很难给它下定义。
While pinning down a definition has proven tricky, the general consensus is it’s some means of information gathering.
虽然事实证明，确定好奇心的定义颇为棘手，但普遍的共识是，它是某种收集信息的手段。
Psychologists also agree curiosity is intrinsically motivated.
心理学家们还一致认为，好奇心是由内在动机驱动的。
Curiosity covers such a large set of behaviors that there probably isn’t any single “curiosity gene” that makes humans wonder about and explore their environment.
好奇心涵盖的行为如此广泛，以至于很可能并不存在任何单一的“好奇心基因”，能让人类对周围环境感到好奇并加以探索。
That said, curiosity does have a genetic component.
话虽如此，好奇心确实含有遗传成分。
Genes and the environment interact in many complex ways to shape individuals and guide their behavior, including their curiosity.
基因与环境以许多复杂的方式相互作用，塑造个体并引导其行为，其中也包括好奇心。
Regardless of their genetic makeup, infants have to learn an incredible amount of information in a short time, and curiosity is one of the tools humans have found to accomplish that gigantic task.
无论基因构成如何，婴儿都必须在短时间内学习数量惊人的信息，好奇心则是人类为完成这项庞大任务而找到的工具之一。
Hundreds of studies show that infants prefer novelty.
数百项研究表明，婴儿偏爱新奇事物。
It’s what motivates non-human animals, human infants and probably human adults to explore and seek out new things before growing less interested in them after continued exposure.
正是这种对新奇事物的偏好，驱使非人类动物、人类婴儿，很可能还有人类成年人，去探索、寻找新事物，而在持续接触之后，他们对这些事物的兴趣又会逐渐减弱。
But curiosity often comes with a cost.
但好奇心往往伴随着代价。
In some situations, the stakes are low and failure is a healthy part of growth.
在有些情况下，利害关系不大，失败是成长中有益的一部分。
For instance, many babies are perfectly proficient crawlers, but they decide to try walking because there’s more to see and do when they stand upright.
例如，许多婴儿已经爬得非常熟练，却还是决定尝试走路，因为站起来以后，能看的、能做的都更多。
But this milestone comes at a small cost.
但达到这一里程碑，是要付出一点小代价的。
A study of 12- to 19-month-olds learning how to walk documented that these children fell down a lot.
一项研究以12到19个月大、正在学走路的幼儿为对象，记录到这些孩子经常摔倒。
Seventeen times per hour, to be exact.
确切地说，是每小时十七次。
But walking is faster than crawling, so this motivates expert crawlers to transition to walking.
但走路比爬行快，所以这会促使爬行高手过渡到走路。
Sometimes, however, testing out a new idea can lead to disaster.
然而，有时尝试新想法可能会导致灾难。
For instance, the Inuit people of the Arctic regions have created incredible ways to deal with the challenges of living in northern climates, but what we forget about are the tens of thousands of people that tried and failed to make it in those challenging landscapes.
例如，北极地区的因纽特人创造了令人惊叹的方法，来应对在北方气候条件下生活的种种挑战；但我们忘记的是，还有数以万计的人曾试图在那些充满挑战的地域立足，却以失败告终。